Hui Ye

Room 6024, 18 Tat Chee Avenue, Kowloon, Hong Kong \$\\$\\$\\$+852-65769246

■ huiyehci@gmail.com

Research Focus

My research interests lie in the intersection of Human-Computer Interaction (HCI) and Computer Graphics (CG). Specifically, my main research focus is on exploring novel mobile AR prototyping tools and techniques for 3D contents and interactions.

Education

City University of Hong Kong (CityU)

Sep 2017-Aug 2022

Ph.D. in Creative Media Supervisor: Prof. Hongbo Fu

Thesis: 3D Content and Interaction Prototyping with Mobile Augmented Reality

• University of Science and Technology of China (USTC)

Sep 2012-June 2016

B.A. in Communication

Minor in Computer Science and Technology

Experience

 Research Assistant, City University of Hong Kong Supervisor: Prof. Hongbo Fu Sep 2021-Aug 2022

 Visiting Ph.D. student, Tsinghua University Institute of HCI and Media Integration Advisor: Dr. Chun Yu and Prof. Hongbo Fu

Dec 2019-Apr 2020

 City University of Hong Kong Exchange student Sep-Dec 2014

Publications

- Hui Ye and Hongbo Fu. 2022. ProGesAR: Mobile AR Prototyping for Proxemic and Gestural Interactions with Real-world IoT Enhanced Spaces. In *Proceedings of the 2022 CHI Conference on Human* Factors in Computing Systems (CHI 2022).
- **Hui Ye**, Kin Chung Kwan, and Hongbo Fu. 2021. 3D Curve Creation on and around Physical Objects with Mobile AR. In *IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics (TVCG*).
- Hui Ye, Kin Chung Kwan (joint first author), Wanchao Su, and Hongbo Fu. 2020. ARAnimator: In-situ Character Animation in Mobile AR with User-defined Motion Gestures. In ACM Transactions on Graphics (Special Issue of ACM SIGGRAPH 2020).
- Wanchao Su, Hui Ye, Shuyu Chen, Lin Gao, and Hongbo Fu. 2022. DrawingInStyles: Portrait Image Generation and Editing with Spatially Conditioned StyleGAN. In *IEEE Transactions on Visualization* and Computer Graphics (TVCG). Accepted for publication.
- Xuanyu Wang, Hui Ye, Christian Sandor, Weizhan Zhang, and Hongbo Fu. 2022. Predict-and-Drive: Avatar Motion Adaption in Room-Scale Augmented Reality Telepresence with Heterogeneous Spaces. In IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics (TVCG): Special Issue for IEEE ISMAR 2022. Accepted for publication.
- Yanxiang Zhang and **Hui Ye**. 2016. Time-Based Nonlinear Interactive Player. In *International Conference on Augmented Reality, Virtual Reality and Computer Graphics*. Springer, Cham.

• Yanxiang Zhang, Yun Zhu, **Hui Ye**. 2015. The Design of an Augmented Reality Based Rigid Body Motion Experiment System. In *Applied Mechanics and Materials*. Trans Tech Publications Ltd.

0 1	1 . 1	T 1	r /	0 A 1
50	lected		innors a	& Awards
			LOILOID (S ILVVUIGO

RGC Postdoctoral Fellowship	2022
 Outstanding Academic Performance Award of CityU 	2021
Shidi CAD&CG Excellent Student Award	2021
Research Tuition Scholarship of CityU	2020
o Guo Moruo Scholarship (Top 2%, Highest Honor for USTC Undergraduates)	2016
 Merit Graduate of Anhui Province & USTC (Top 3%) 	2016
 Certificate of Honorary Rank of USTC (Top 5%) 	2016
 Outstanding Thesis of USTC 	2016
Sun Bin Leadership Scholarship of USTC	2014
 Aegon-Industrial Responsibility Scholarship of USTC 	2014
 Outstanding Instructor in "Science and Technology Week" of USTC 	2013-15
 Gold Award of Excellent Student Scholarship of USTC (Top 5%) 	2013
 Outstanding Young Volunteer of USTC 	2013
Talks	
 ProGesAR: Mobile AR Prototyping for Proxemic and Gestural Interactions with Real-worldIoT Enhanced Spaces Conference Paper Presenter, CHI 2022 	May 2022
 Mobile AR Prototyping for Proxemic and Gestural Interactions Invited Speaker, EAA Youth Academic Forum, Tianjin Fine Arts Institute 	Apr 2022
 Exploring Novel Mobile AR Prototyping Techniques and Tools for 3D Contents and Interactions SIGGRAPH Thesis Fast Forward 	Dec 2021
 ARAnimator: In-situ Character Animation in Mobile AR with User-defined Motion Gestures 	
Invited Speaker, Graphics And Mixed Environment Symposium (GAMES) Invited Speaker, SCM ACIM Colloquium, CityU Conference Paper Presenter, SIGGRAPH 2020	Sep 2021 Oct 2020 Aug 2020
 3D Curve Creation on and around Physical Objects with Mobile AR Invited Speaker, IEEE VR 2021 	Mar 2021
In-situ 3D Content Creation in Mobile AR	Mar 2021

Teaching Experience

 Teaching Assistant, CityU SM1103A Introduction to Media Computing 	2018 & 19 Fall
 Teaching Assistant, CityU SM2716 Physical Computing & Tangible Media 	2018 Spring

Professional Service

 Paper Review: SIGGRAPH Asia 2022, CHI 2022 & 2020, UIST 2022, MobileHCI 2022, TVCG 2022, IEEE VR 2021, IEEE AIVR 2021, PG 2020

- Competition Jury: Jury Member of CHI 2022 Student Research Competition
- Student Helper: PG 2018

Skills

- Programming Language: C#, Swift, Python, HTML
- **Graphics interface**: OpenCV, QT
- Application Tools: iOS App, ARKit, HoloLens App, Mixed Reality Toolkit
- Hardware: HoloLens, Arduino, Motion Capture